(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
オーバーバード
Overbird
四六時中 帰りの会で
All day long, at the closing meeting,
めんどくささを 押し付けられてる
being forced to deal with all the hassle.
なにかの間に間に
In the midst of something...
師走はやめて まとめ役なら
Stop it with December. If you're the coordinator...
聞くを上手に おなじみ合ってる
...you're good at listening, as we're used to each other.
仲良しこよしだ
We're the best of friends.
さあ だっ だっ だっ だ 黙れ 黙れよ
Now, da-da-da-da, shut up, shut up.
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ 静かにしてほしいね
I just want you to be a little quiet.
ああ 私達 待望へ
Ah, we are heading for the long-awaited.
世界てんてんてんぱく Yeah Yeah Yeah 果たすその日まで
The world is turning white, Yeah Yeah Yeah, until the day it's fulfilled.
れれれ 煉獄 Yeah Yeah Yeah あなたの周りも Yeah Yeah
Re-re-re Purgatory, Yeah Yeah Yeah, around you too, Yeah Yeah.
境界線 線 全て あれあれあれや 約束の地まで
Boundary lines, all that, oh, oh, oh, until the promised land.
さあ掲げよ バッテン バッテン てんてんてんぱく Yeah Yeah Yeah
Now hold up the cross, cross, turning white, Yeah Yeah Yeah.
今日も来ない そっちのけだね 家に成るから
You're not coming today either, neglecting me, because I'm becoming home.
私一人でも やっておきますね
Even if I'm alone, I'll get it done.
すべて すべて すべて 任せて それをさせてよ
Leave everything, everything, everything to me, let me do that.
大事なことなの わかっているでしょう
It's an important thing, you know that, right?
四六時中 帰りの階段 めんどくさいまま
All day long, the stairs back home, feeling troublesome.
今日も明日も 過ぎていくのでしょう
Today and tomorrow will probably pass by.
花瓶に水をあげましょう
Let's water the vase.
刻の中 萎れたこと 忘れてた
In time, I forgot that things had withered.
さあ だっ だっ だっ だ 黙れ 黙れよ
Now, da-da-da-da, shut up, shut up.
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words.
少しだけ 静かにしてほしいね
I just want you to be a little quiet.
ああ 私達 待望へ
Ah, we are heading for the long-awaited.
夢と未来 見たかったはずなのに
I should have wanted to see dreams and the future.
世界てんてんてんぱく Yeah Yeah Yeah 見えずその日まで
The world is turning white, Yeah Yeah Yeah, until that day when it's unseen.
だっ だっ だっ だっ 永遠 この世の理 Yeah Yeah Yeah
Da, da, da, da, eternity, the truth of this world, Yeah Yeah Yeah.
今はてんてんてん さあ さあ さあ あなたの待ち中
Now it's... come on, come on, come on, while waiting for you.
片手で作るはバッテン さあ世界てんてんてんぱく Yeah Yeah Yeah
Making a cross with one hand, now the world is turning white, Yeah Yeah Yeah.
果たすその日まで れれれ 煉獄 Yeah Yeah Yeah
Until the day it's fulfilled, re-re-re Purgatory, Yeah Yeah Yeah.
あなたの周りも Yeah Yeah 境界線 線 全て あれあれあれや
Around you too, Yeah Yeah, boundary lines, all that, oh, oh, oh.
約束の地まで さあ掲げよ バッテン バッテン
Until the promised land, now hold up the cross, cross.
てんてんてん しんたらびてんじのワインをあけましょう
Turning... let's open the wine of the heavens.
ねえ あたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me...
気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて
Notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me.
夢を見せてよ
Show me a dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why don't you understand?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you.
二度と触れないで
Never touch me again.
バラサイト
Parasite
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
ちょっと待って どこからおかしくなったの？
Wait a minute, where did it go wrong?
ダメなとこも好きになれて よかったのに
It was fine that I could even love your bad parts.
パッと呑んで誰かに埋めてもらえたら
If I could just drink it up and have someone fill the void...
あなたのこと忘れられると 思っていた
I thought I could forget about you.
トモダチってさ 都合よくないけど
Being "friends" isn't exactly convenient,
繋がってるなら 悪くはないね
But if we're connected, it's not so bad.
騙し騙し生きて病んじゃって
Living by deceiving ourselves and getting sick,
優しくされると余計にツライ
Being treated kindly makes it even more painful.
けど冷たくされるの望んでないの
But I don't want to be treated coldly.
あたしだけでいいよって信じちゃって バカだ
Believing that "just me is enough"... I'm an idiot.
ねえ あたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me...
気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて
Notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me.
夢を見せてよ
Show me a dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why don't you understand?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you.
二度と触れないで
Never touch me again.
小さい感情は 1・2・の…で流れ星
Tiny emotions, 1, 2... and they're shooting stars.
あの子のこと 呪ってあげるわ
I'll put a curse on that girl for you.
ねえ 愛した時間を返してよ
Hey, give me back the time I spent loving you.
嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき
Liar, liar, liar, liar.
でもまだ好きだよ
But I still love you.
吸って吐いて そう ちゃんと生きて
Inhale, exhale, yeah, live properly.
鼓膜舐める愛のCoda
The coda of love that licks my eardrums.
溶かし尽くす煙るSoda
A smoky soda that melts everything away.
ねえ 置いていかないで
Hey, don't leave me behind.
吐いて、燃えないゴミにするんだ。
I'll spit it out and turn it into non-burnable trash.
なんで　なんで
Why? Why?
なんで　なんで　なんで　なんで
Why? Why? Why? Why?
なんで　なんで
Why? Why?
ねえ　あたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you like me...
気付いて　気付いて　気付いて　気付いて
Notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me!
夢を見せてよ
Show me a dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの
Why won't you understand?
嫌いだ　嫌いだ　嫌いだ　嫌いだ　大嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you so much!
あなたの振り向かないの
You don't even look back.
気付いてる　気付いてる　気付いてる　気付いてる
You know, you know, you know, you know...
くせに　あたしはどうしてバカ変われないの
Even though you know, why am I such a fool who can't change?
したいよ　したいよ　したいよ　したいよ
I want to, I want to, I want to, I want to...
離れたくないよ
I don't want to leave you.
かさなる感情　流れ星　1... 2... の合図で
Overlapping emotions, a shooting star, at the signal of 1... 2...
あの人のこと祝ってあげるわ
I'll celebrate that person for you.
ねえ　最期にギュッとさせてほしい
Hey, let me hold you tight one last time.
ありがとう　ありがとう　ありがとう　ありがとう
Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.
これであなたも...
With this, you too...
往生しようぜこの浮世は三千里
Let's give it up, this fleeting world is three thousand miles.
雨曝して隠遁　甘酸っぱいばっかのアイロニー
Left in the rain, in seclusion, an irony full of only bittersweetness.
微糖じゃ達しないどうせこの日々は忙しない
A little sweetness won't suffice, these days are busy anyway.
ちょっと目が合った手と手と
Our eyes met for a second, hand in hand.
現せその声で
Show it with that voice of yours.
あー　遊び遊ばせて
Ah, let me play and be played with.
手の鳴る方へ
To where the hands clap.
浅ましい　喧しい
Miserable and noisy.
喧しい
Noisy.
泣きっ面に蜂逃げ場もなくて
Misfortunes pile up with nowhere to run.
ほら、この夜は空騒ぎ
Look, this night is much ado about nothing.
想像したってこの浮世は三千里
Even in imagination, this fleeting world is three thousand miles.
空回りの毎日　疑って焦っては怠惰に
Spinning wheels every day, doubting and rushing into laziness.
哀落は日々忙しない　そぞろに吹くは青嵐
The days of decline are busy, a sudden summer wind blows.
まともに見つめ合った目と目と
Our eyes met properly for a moment.
あの人は恋敵
That person is a love rival.
混じり合えない　二人
Two people who can't mix together.
小波浮世に　身を任せたら
Leaving myself to the ripples of this fleeting world.
もう左様なら知らない街で
Goodbye now, in a city I don't know.
また出会いましょう
Let's meet again.
あー　遊び遊ばせて
Ah, let me play and be played with.
手の鳴る方へ
To where the hands clap.
見惚れて射止めて
Be fascinated and shoot through.
恋心
A heart in love.
花びらハラヒラ舞いふたつ
Two flower petals fluttering and dancing.
法螺、あの人も嘘つき？
Look, is that person a liar too?
あー　遊び遊ばせて
Ah, let me play and be played with.
手の鳴る方へ
To where the hands clap.
浅ましい　喧しい
Miserable and noisy.
喧しい
Noisy.
飲み干せ飽くまで果てるまで
Drink it up to your heart's content, until the very end.
なんせこの夜は寂しがり
After all, this night is a lonely one.
間抜けな醜態だ金輪際のさよなら
What a foolish sight, a final goodbye.
求め合うほどに罪深き
The more we seek each other, the more sinful it becomes.
飲み干せ飽くまで果てるまで
Drink it up to your heart's content, until the very end.
なんせこの世は救いあり
After all, there is salvation in this world.
あー　遊び遊ばせて
Ah, let me play and be played with.
手の鳴る方へ
To where the hands clap.
この世は猿芝居
This world is a monkey show.
歪んで傷だらけの春
A distorted spring, covered in wounds.
麻酔も打たずに歩いた
I walked without even having anesthesia.
体の奥底で響く
Echoing deep within my body.
生き足りないと強く
Strongly feeling I haven't lived enough.
まだ味わうさ　噛み終えたガムの味
I'll still taste it, the flavor of a chewed-up piece of gum.
冷めきれないままの心で
With a heart that still hasn't cooled down.
一つ一つ失くした果てに
After losing things one by one...
ようやく残ったもの
...the things that finally remained.
これが愛じゃなければ
If this isn't love,
何と呼ぶのか 僕は知らなかった
what do I call it? I didn't know.
呼べよ 花の名前を
Call it, a flower's name,
ただ一つだけ
just one.
張り裂けるくらいに
As if it's about to burst.
鼻先が触れる
Our noses touch,
呼吸が止まる
our breaths stop.
痛みは消えないままでいい
The pain is fine just as it is.
疲れたその目で 何を言う
What do you say with those tired eyes?
傷跡隠して 歩いた
Hiding your scars, you walked.
そのくせ 影をばらまいた
Yet, you scattered shadows.
気づいてほしかった
I wanted you to notice.
また歩けるか 噛み締めた砂の味
Can I walk again? The taste of sand I chewed.
夜露で濡れた 芝生の上
On the grass wet with night dew.
逸る胸に 尋ねる言葉
Words asked to my racing heart.
終わるには まだ早いだろう
It's too early to end, isn't it?
誰もが正しまるように
So that everyone would be correct,
微笑むことが上手く出来なかった
I couldn't smile well.
ひとつだに ひとつでいい 守れるだけで
Just one, just one is fine, if I can just protect it.
それでよかったのに
That would have been enough.
あまりにくだらない願いが消えない
This so foolish wish won't disappear.
誰にも奪えない魂
A soul that no one can take away.
何に例えよう 君と僕を
What shall I compare us to?
踵に残る 似た傷を
To the similar scars remaining on our heels.
晴れ間を呼べば まだ続く
If we call for the sunlight, it will still continue.
行こう
Let's go.
花も咲かないうちに
Before even the flowers bloom.
これが愛じゃなければ
If this isn't love,
何と呼ぶのか 僕は知らなかった
what do I call it? I didn't know.
呼べよ 恐れるままに
Call it, as you are afraid,
花の名前を
the flower's name.
君じゃなきゃダメだと
That it had to be you.
鼻先が触れる
Our noses touch,
呼吸が止まる
our breaths stop.
痛みは消えないままでいい
The pain is fine just as it is.
あまりにくだらない願いが消えない
This so foolish wish won't disappear.
止まない
It won't stop.
はい、ということで、4曲連続で聴いていただきました！
Yes, and with that, you've listened to four songs in a row!
皆様、待ったかね！
Everyone, wait for me!
ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します！
I am Takane Lui, the female executive of HoloX!
2周年だー！イェイイェイイェイイェイ！
It's the 2nd anniversary! Yay yay yay yay!
あ、ダンサーさんもありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you to the dancers too!
はい、ということでね、ちょっと息を整えたいんだけど…
Yes, and so, I want to catch my breath a bit, but...
…いける！
...I can do it!
ということで、鷹嶺ルイ2周年ライブ『ANIMAL』が始まりましたー！
And so, Takane Lui's 2nd anniversary live "ANIMAL" has begun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆様、楽しんでおりますでしょうか！
Is everyone enjoying themselves?
今回もね、あの、ハッシュタグございますので。あ、こっちかな？
This time too, um, we have a hashtag. Oh, is it this way?
こっちかな？ここにありますので。
Is it this way? It's right here.
よかったらたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot if you'd like!
ちゃんと「ポスト」って言えました。
I managed to say "post" properly.
はい、ということでね、今回『ANIMAL』というタイトルをライブに使わせてもらったんですけど。
Yes, and so, this time I used the title "ANIMAL" for the live.
まあ、その意味もね、まあ後々わかると思うのです。
Well, the meaning behind that, well, I think you'll understand later.
『ANIMAL』ね、ちょっと皆様もお気づきかと思いますが、
About "ANIMAL," I think some of you might have noticed already, but...
なんと、曲名すべてね、動物の名前が入っている曲を歌わせてもらっております！
Unbelievably, I'm singing songs where all the titles include animal names!
アニマル...
Animal...
あ、パラサイトは寄生生物なんだけど、まあね、命あるものみんな動物なんで、そういうところは気にしない気にしないね。
Ah, Parasite is a parasitic organism, but well, everything that lives is an animal, so don't worry about that.
そうだよね？
Right?
気にしない、気にしないということで。
We won't worry about it. So,
演出とかもね、すごい今までの、ちょっとこういうことやりたかったなっていうのをたくさん爆盛りさせていただいておるのですが、
For the production, I've packed in a lot of things that I've wanted to do for a long time,
このね、後しかも、えー、テンポラリーダンスをちょっとダンサーさんにしていただきまして、
And after this... I had dancers from Temporary Dance perform for me,
えー、ちょっと私が歌っている周りを回ってもらうっていうね、演出をしていただきました。
I had them perform by dancing around me while I sang.
ありがとうございます。すごいやりたかったんで、助かりました。
Thank you very much. I really wanted to do that, so it was a big help.
そしていろいろこだわりはこの後もあるんですけど、
And I have more specific things I'm picky about later on, but
ちょっと大きなね、こだわりとして、このステージ、皆さん見てください。このステージ、
as for a big point of pride, please look at this stage, everyone. This stage...
本当にすごくないですか？ いやさ、
...isn't it truly amazing? I mean,
こういう、あのステージで、ちょっと歌いたいですっていうことで、
I said I wanted to sing on a stage like this,
すごいなんか、あの難しいそうな顔してたんだけど、
and although they looked quite troubled at first,
「いや、いけます」ってすごい自信を持ってね、ちょっと言ってくださって。
they told me with such confidence, "We can do it."
で、本当にできんのかなって私ちょっと不安だったんですけど、
I was a bit worried if they could really pull it off,
これ仕上がってみて、もう大満足っていうか、私の想像を超えていった、
but seeing it finished, I'm fully satisfied—or rather, it exceeded my expectations,
あのステージでこう歌えるっていうのは本当にもう、本日幸せでございます。
and being able to sing on a stage like this today makes me so happy.
なのでね、あのたくさん細かいところまで、えー、作っていただきましたので、そちらも注目してみていただければなと思います。
They've paid attention to every detail, so I hope you'll look closely at everything.
そして、えー、次の曲も、なんと、ちょっとした演出がありますので、
And for the next song, there's actually a bit of a special production,
ここのステージをね、ちょっと演出の都合上、ガラッと変えさせていただきます。
so we're going to change the stage completely for the performance.
そして私が水を飲みたいのもありますので、えーダンサーさんもね、ちょっとね、はけるということで。
I also need to drink some water, and the dancers will be heading off stage.
ということで、一緒にじゃあ、あのバイバイして、ちょっと一瞬待ってもらいましょう、皆さんに。
So, let's say goodbye together and have everyone wait for just a moment.
ということで、えー、みんな待っててねー！
So, everyone, please wait!
はーい！ということでお待たせ、みんな待ったかねー？
Hi! Thanks for waiting, everyone! Did you wait long?
ちょっとお水休憩も挟み、そして、じゃじゃーん！ピアノをね、用意していただきました。
I took a water break, and ta-da! They've prepared a piano for me.
ということは次はこちらですね、そう。その通り。
Which means, next is... that's right!
えー、ピアノの、えー、伴奏でちょっと歌わせていただければなと思います。
Yes, I'd like to sing with piano accompaniment.
そう、あの弾き語りできたらいいんだけど、弾き語りはできないので、
I wish I could play and sing myself, but since I can't,
ピアノを弾いてくださる方をちょっと紹介したいと思います。ウイングさーん！
I'd like to introduce the person who will be playing for me. Wing-san!
本日はよろしくお願いします。
Thank you for being here today.
それでは、ご準備の方をよろしくお願いします。
Well then, please get ready.
ということで、ちょっとピアノバージョンでお送りするわけなんで、ちょっと緊張してるんですけど、
So, since it's a piano version, I'm feeling a bit nervous,
心を込めてね、歌いたいと思います。この後にね、ウイングさんとメンバーシップライブも行いますので、
but I'll sing with all my heart. After this, I'll be doing a membership live with Wing-san,
よかったらメンバーシップに入っていただけると嬉しいです。楽しみにしててね。
so I'd be happy if you joined the membership. Look forward to it!
ということで、準備大丈夫ですか？ ウイングさん。
So, are you ready, Wing-san?
ということで、歌っていきましょう。
Well then, let's sing.
それでは聞いてください。ピアノバージョンです。レオ。
Please listen. This is the piano version of Leo.
レオ
作詞・作曲：優里
Leo
Lyrics & Composition: Yuuri
ショーケースの中過ごしていた
I spent my time inside a showcase
誰もかれもが過ぎ去っていた
Everyone was just passing by
怖かったんだ あの日君に連れられるまでは
I was scared until that day you took me away
僕と同じの小さな手
A small hand just like mine
転げまわりくすぐりあう僕ら
Rolling around, we'd tickle each other
こんなに君の事好きになってた
Just like that, I came to love you
どんなときでも傍に居て
No matter when, staying by your side
君が言うなら ああ
If you say so, ah...
名前はレオ 名前呼んでよ
My name is Leo, call my name
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because it's the name you gave to me
嬉しい日も 悲しい日も
The happy days and the sad days too
傍に居ると決めた大事な人
Staying by your side, my precious person
The precious person I decided to stay beside
君が大きくなるほどに
僕との時間は減るが道理
As you grow larger,
it's only natural our time together decreases
遠くに君の友達同士
仕方がないよなぁ
Your friends are in the distance,
it can't be helped, right?
最近つけるその香水
鼻の利く僕にとっては辛いや
That perfume you've been wearing lately
is hard on my sensitive nose
今日も帰りは遅くなるんだろうか
Will you be coming home late again today?
君が居ない部屋
夢を見る
In the room where you're not here,
I dream
あの日のこと
また
About that day,
again
名前はレオ
名前呼んでよ
The name is Leo,
call my name
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because it's the name you gave me
寂しいけれど
悲しいけれど
Though it's lonely,
though it's sad
傍に居ると決めた大事な人
The precious person I decided to stay beside
君が誰かと暮らすことを
That you are living with someone else
伝えに帰ってきた夜に
On the night you came back to tell me
撫でてくれたね
きっとお別れだね
You stroked me, didn't you?
It's surely goodbye
最後にさ
会えたから
ねえ　幸せだよ
Because we could meet at the end,
hey, I'm happy
名前はレオ
名前呼んでよ
The name is Leo,
call my name
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because it's the name you gave me
もう泣かないでよ
名前呼んでよ
Don't cry anymore,
call my name
あの日より大きな手で撫でてくれた
You stroked me with a hand larger than that day
名前はレオ
名前呼んでよ
The name is Leo,
call my name
君がくれた名前で良かったよ
I'm glad for the name you gave me
忘れないでよ
それでいいんだよ
Don't forget,
that's enough
新しい誰かにまた名前つけて
Give a name to someone new again
突き止めていたい
叶わない君の正体は
I want to track it down,
your unattainable true identity
迷宮入りの
難解なミステリー
An unsolved,
difficult mystery
心変わり　色変わり
軽やかに姿を変えたのは
The change of heart, change of color,
the one who nimbly changed form
悲しいほどの夕暮れ
Was the twilight, sad to the core
僕の知らない君は誰
Who are you, the one I don't know?
カメレオン
Chameleon
作詞・作曲：常田大希
Lyrics/Composition: Daiki Tsuneta
急行列車が通り過ぎた
The express train passed by
寂れた駅のホームには隙間風が吹き抜け
A draft blew through the deserted station platform
君の姿はどこにも見当たらなくて
Your figure was nowhere to be found
時を経て通話画面に映った君は
The you who appeared on the call screen
after some time
もう僕の知らない君でした
Was already a you that I didn't know
幸せそうに笑うから
つられて僕も笑ってしまった
Because you laughed so happily,
I ended up laughing along too
何度でも何度でも塗り潰して
Painting over it again and again
汚れた悲しみの上から白い絵の具で
With white paint over the stained sadness
全てを台無しにして葬り去ってしまった夜さえ
Even the night I ruined everything
and buried it away
キャンバスは色付くから
涙にじんで見えなくても
Because the canvas takes color,
even if it's blurred by tears and hard to see
記憶の中の君と
The you in my memories and
今の君はどちらも真実で
the you now are both the truth,
鮮やかに色めく君はもう僕の知らない色
You, blooming vividly, are already a color I don't know.
何度でも 何度でも塗りつぶして
Over and over again, over and over again, paint over it.
今の君にお似合いの何色でも構わないの
Any color that suits the you now is fine by me.
伝えたいこの想い それすら叶わないけど
I want to convey these feelings, though even that won't come true.
口にすれば単純な強がり
If I put it into words, it's just simple bravado.
お隣に僕がいなくても
Even if I'm not by your side.
きっと 迷わない君の焦点は
Surely, your focus that won't waver
迷い入る 難解なミステリー
enters a stray, difficult mystery.
いつだって 軽やかに姿を変えていくのは
The thing that's always lightly changing its form
悲しいほど夕映え
is the evening glow, so sad.
僕の知らない君は誰
Who is the you that I don't know?
信号は青なのか それとも緑なのか
Is the traffic light blue or is it green?
どっちなんだ？ あやふやなものははっきりさせたい
Which is it? I want to make vague things clear.
夕暮れ時の商店街の雑踏を通り抜けるのが面倒で
It's a hassle to go through the crowd of the shopping street at dusk,
踏切の手前で 止まって帰る
so I stop before the railroad crossing and go home.
放課後の教室は苦手だ
I'm not good at the classroom after school.
その場にいるだけで分かり合えてるようで
Just being there, it's like we understand each other.
話し合いにならないし しらけてしまった僕は無口になる
It doesn't lead to a talk, and I, disillusioned, become silent.
言いたいこと言い合って 解決しようだなんて楽天的なんだよ
Talking things through to solve them is so optimistic.
誰かが溜息をついた
Someone sighed.
そう それが本当の声だろう
Yes, that must be the real voice.
黒い羊 そうだ 僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, yes, it's fine if only I disappear.
そうすれば 止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろう
Then, the needle that had stopped will move again.
全員が納得する そんな答えなんかあるものか
Is there an answer that everyone can agree on?
反対が僕だけなら いっそそうすればいいんだ
If it's only me who opposes, then it's fine that way.
みんなから説得されるほど 居心地悪くなる
The more I'm persuaded, the more uncomfortable I feel.
目配せしてる仲間に は 僕は厄介者でしかない
To my companions exchanging glances, I'm just a nuisance.
真っ白な群れに悪目立ちしてる
Standing out poorly in a pure white flock,
自分だけが真っ黒な羊
only I am a pitch black sheep.
と言ったって同じ色に染まりたくないんだ
Even so, I don't want to be dyed in the same color.
薄暗い部屋の明かりつけるタイミングって一体いつなんだろう
When on earth is the timing to turn on the light in a dim room?
スマホには愛のない 過去だけが残ってる
Only the loveless past remains on the smartphone.
人間関係の答え合わせなんか 到底できないし
Finding answers to relationships is impossible,
そこにいなければ よかったと後悔する
I regret and wish I hadn't been there.
人生の大半は 思うようにはいかない
Most of life doesn't go as you'd like.
納得できないことばかりだし 諦めろと説得されてきたけど
It's full of disagreements; I've been told to give up,
それならやっぱ納得なんかしないまま その度に何度も唾を
if so, I won't agree and will just spit every time,
吐いて 噛み付いていきませんか
won't you spit and bite back with me?
No No No No
全部 僕のせいだ
It's all my fault.
黒い羊 そうだ 僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, yes, it's fine if only I disappear.
そうすれば 止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろう
Then, the needle that had stopped will move again.
全員が納得する そんな答えなんかあるものか
Is there an answer that everyone can agree on?
反対が僕だけなら いっそそうすればいいんだ
If it's only me who opposes, then it's fine that way.
みんなから説得されるほど 居心地悪くなる
The more I'm persuaded, the more uncomfortable I feel.
目配せしてる仲間に は 僕は厄介者でしかない
To my companions exchanging glances, I'm just a nuisance.
分かってるよ
I know.
黒い羊
Black Sheep
白い羊なんて僕は絶対なりたくないんだ
I never want to become a white sheep.
そうなった瞬間に僕は僕じゃなくなってしまうよ
The moment I do, I will no longer be myself.
周りと違う そのことで
Just because I'm different from those around me,
誰かに迷惑かけたか?
did I cause anyone trouble?
髪の毛を染めろという大人は何が気に入らない?
What don't adults like, telling me to dye my hair?
反逆の象徴になるとでも思っているのか?
Do they think I'm becoming a symbol of rebellion?
自分の色とは違う
Is being a different color from theirs
それだけで厄介者か? Oh
enough to make me a nuisance? Oh.
自らの真実を捨て 白い羊の振りをする者よ
You, who throw away your own truth and pretend to be a white sheep.
黒い羊を見つけ指を差して笑うのか?
Will you find a black sheep, point at it, and laugh?
それならば僕はいつだって それでも僕はいつだって
In that case, I will always... Even so, I will always...
ここで悪目立ちしてよう
stand out for the wrong reasons here.
RAD DOGS
ヘッドホン外して 独りきり歩く街
Taking off my headphones, I walk alone through the city.
迷っているのか 間違っているのか 知らない場所みたいだ
Am I lost, or am I wrong? It feels like an unfamiliar place.
見えない進行
Unseen progression,
感じない心配
unfelt worry.
俺に回らないものばかりだ
It's full of things that don't come my way.
なんのストーリー
What story?
誰のストーリー
Whose story?
手に入んなきゃ欲しくなる そうだろ
If I can't have it, I'll want it. Right?
合図くれよ
Give me a signal,
マイクかざせ
hold up the mic.
合図は今
The signal is now,
追い風に
in the tailwind,
なびいていく
fluttering along.
チャンスは来た
The chance has come.
ダイブ寸前 Hater
Just about to dive, hater.
今リスタート決めてはじめさ
Deciding on a restart now, let's begin.
見たいならそれだけでいいでしょ
If you want to see, that should be enough, right?
理由なんて知らない
I don't know the reason,
理由なんていらない
I don't need a reason.
運命論にあらがって
Resisting fatalism.
今リスタート決めて弾けさ
Deciding on a restart now, let's burst forth.
見たいならそれだけでいいでしょ
If you want to see, that should be enough, right?
内なる声 Groovy
Inner voice, groovy.
聞かせてよ Heartbeat
Let me hear your heartbeat.
立ち止まる暇なんてないから
Because there's no time to stand still.
Hey-O AH AH Mike Check 1,2
Hey-O AH AH Mike Check 1, 2
オールナイトでも豪快冒険
Grand adventure even all night long.
とか言う前マジで女優潮流掻き急な者共
Before you say anything, people rushing through the tide.
RADでBADなUNDER DOGがビビっときたね ビビっとに染まれ
The rad and bad underdog felt a spark. Get dyed in that spark.
上しか見てねぇ今日のお前は 秘める闘志の悩める勝ち犬
You today, looking only upwards. A winning dog struggling with hidden spirit.
合図くれよ
Give me a signal,
マイクかざせ
hold up the mic.
俺らは今
We are now,
追い風に
in the tailwind,
なびいていく
fluttering along.
チャンスは来た
The chance has come.
ダイブ寸前 Hater
Just about to dive, hater.
今リスタート決めてはじめさ
Deciding on a restart now, let's begin.
見たいならそれだけでいいでしょ
If you want to see, that should be enough, right?
理由なんて知らない
I don't know the reason,
理由なんていらない
I don't need a reason.
背徳の快感 始まって
The pleasure of immorality has begun.
今リスタート決めて弾けさ
Deciding on a restart now, let's burst forth.
見たいならそれだけでいいでしょ
If you want to see, that should be enough, right?
内なら声 Groovy
Inner voice, groovy.
聞かせてよ Heartbeat
Let me hear your heartbeat.
立ち止まる暇なんてないから
Because there's no time to stand still.
追い風に吹かれて Yeah
Blown by the tailwind, yeah.
Alright 振り向かず進んで
Alright, keep moving forward without looking back.
キャットラビング
Cat Loving
作詞・作曲/ 香椎モイミ
Music & Lyrics / Moimi Kashii
痛いことは嫌いですが 君の手のひらは嫌いじゃない
I don't like things that hurt, but I don't hate your palms.
言葉は飴玉みたいに 甘く広がって心満たせ
Let words spread like candy, sweet and filling my heart.
あー全然分かってない
Ah, you don't understand at all.
永遠に言う通り
Forever doing as I'm told.
完全にフェアじゃない
It's completely unfair.
(どこにいても) あー何で？は聞いていない
(No matter where I am) Ah, "Why?" doesn't work.
もっともっとあの子みたいに 可愛くならなくちゃ
I have to become cuter and cuter, just like that girl.
愛情は染めに 宿命はHow many?
Affection is in the dyeing, fate is... How many?
もう一体誰のだって分かんなくなる
I can't even tell whose it is anymore.
延命またたび 週に二ご褒美
Life-prolonging catnip, a reward twice a week.
「もう嫌んなった」って離されないように
So I won't be let go of even if I say "I'm sick of this."
今日だってちゃんとお膝で ほんと内緒の手繕い
Today too, properly on your lap, a truly secret grooming.
にゃんって良い子にするから愛して
I'll be a good girl and go "Meow", so love me.
Everybody Today is a rubbing day. Get in Get in this is my catnip.
Any Any Any time is fine. Gimme Gimme Run with me my darling.
会いたいを間違いなんて皆は言う 取り憑かれていって
Everyone says wanting to see you is a mistake, being possessed.
ならこの胸で疼く 締め付けるような切なさは何なの？
Then what is this tightening sorrow aching in my chest?
選ぶ言葉
The words I choose,
戸惑う指先
My hesitant fingertips,
端正な横顔
Your refined profile.
(私しか知らない) あーランダムご機嫌
(I'm the only one who knows) Ah, random moods.
もしかして今日は
Maybe today,
優しく撫でてくれるのかな
You'll pet me gently.
君のそれか耐えられるの 生涯で私だけなんだよね
I'm the only one in the world who can endure you like this.
あからさまにカラダまさに 「もう嫌だ」って離れられないよね そうだよね？
Obviously, my body literally can't leave even if I say "Enough." Right?
感情は徐々に 歌声は少々に
Emotions gradually, vocals just a little.
漏れも冴えるように 転がせば良い
Just let them roll so even leaks are crisp.
柑橘の匂い 立て凌ぐのだ
The smell of citrus, I'll endure it.
もう勝手しか言われぬだけだし
It's not like I can do anything but obey.
今日だってちゃんとお膝で 大人しく
Today too, properly on your lap, behaving.
にゃんってお好きなように 完全淘汰して
Meowing as you please, completely eliminating me.
イェーイ！
Yay!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
おめでとう！一緒だよ！
Congratulations! We're together!
ということでね 今日、そうそうそう今日
And so, today, yes, yes, yes, today.
ということで あの、泥犬と そして我々で2曲連続で出ていただきまして
So, we had RAD DOGS and then us perform two songs in a row.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
いやーどうですか？
So, how was it?
実はね、うちら2周年にして 2人で歌うのは初めて
Actually, even though it's our 2nd anniversary, this is the first time we've sung as a duo.
いやそれ！
Exactly that!
いやそれな！ 何そのテンション
Yeah, that! What's with that energy?
いやそれな！ そう 今日はとっても嬉しい日なのでテンション高いですけれど
Yeah, that! Right, today is a very happy day, so I'm really hyped.
やっぱりさ ホロックスでデビューしてさ 最初うちらだったじゃん、デビューしたのが
After all, when we debuted in HoloX, we were the first ones to debut.
総帥・幹部で出てきて 結構みんなからのこうね、あの注目もあって
Coming out as the Leader and Executive, we got quite a lot of attention from everyone.
で、色々2周年こう、駆け... こう、駆け... 走って、何て言うの？何て言えばいいの？
And for these two years, we've been... been... running... what's the word? How should I say it?
駆け抜けてね！
Dashing through!
あ、そうそうそう！ 駆け抜けてきたね！ 今もうね、疲れで頭が...
Ah, right, right! We've dashed through! My brain is just fried from exhaustion now...
もうずっと歌ってますからね
Well, we've been singing this whole time.
駆け抜けて... きたけど、どう？
We've dashed through... but how was it?
早いようで長かっただ
It felt fast, but also long.
薄い！
Weak!
ねぇ、色々ね 何今日のテンション何なんだよマジで
Right, lots of things... seriously, what is with this energy today?
いやーまあ楽しかったんですよ、今日 めちゃくちゃルイ姉と一緒に踊れてよかったんだね
Well, it's just been so fun today. I'm so glad I could dance with you, Lui-nee.
だって初めてだよ！
Because it's the first time!
そう、そうそうそう しかもホロックスでなんか我輩だけ呼んでくれたってことは なんか...
Right, right, right. And the fact that you called only me from HoloX must mean...
そう、なんか今日は 2周年は ツートップね、あの、ホロックスのツートップ まあ、総帥と幹部で歌って踊りたいなっていうことで お呼びさせていただきました
Yeah, so for today, for the 2nd anniversary, I wanted the two leaders of HoloX, the Leader and Executive, to sing and dance together, which is why I invited you.
いい夫婦
A good couple.
何？今日テンション高いな！
What? You're so high energy today!
そうだよ 嬉しくて体で表してるの いや、めっちゃおめでとう！
That's right! I'm expressing my joy through my body. Seriously, big congrats!
いや、2周年さ、色々あったじゃん お互いさ
Well, lots of things happened over these two years, for both of us.
ありました、とってもありました
There certainly were, very much so.
なんか あの、重要な時は会話したりとかしてたけど まあ、いつもこう静かにお互い見守って
We'd talk during important times, but usually, we just quietly watched over each other.
まあ、なんかやばそうだなと思ったら声かけてみたいなことを... 「大丈夫？」みたいなね
And if it looked like things were getting rough, we'd reach out... like saying "Are you okay?"
そうそうそうそう やってきましたね、ここまで
Exactly. That's how we've made it this far.
やってき、やっぱ応援してもらったし いっぱい応援してもらった、いっぱい応援して 頑張ろうみたいな
We made it, and we were supported by everyone. We got so much support, so let's keep doing our best.
頑張ろうね これからもさ
Let's keep going. From here on out, too.
でね、明日はこより…
And tomorrow is Koyori...
そして、クロヱ、いろはとね…
Then, Chloe and Iroha...
holoXの周年続きますんで、
The holoX anniversaries will continue,
楽しみに… まあ、あいつら破天荒な奴らなんでね。
So look forward to it... Well, they're a wild bunch.
みんな楽しみにしていただければと思います。
I hope everyone looks forward to their streams.
よろしくね、holoXを。
Please continue to support holoX.
ということで、
And with that,
実はですね、この後…
actually, after this...
とある発表と、グッズ紹介を…
a certain announcement and goods introduction...
とある方にしてもらおうと思っております。
will be handled by a certain person.
え？ 我輩？
Eh? Me?
いいえ、違いますよ。違います。
No, you're wrong. It's not you.
なんで！ やりたい！ やりたい！
Why! I want to do it! I want to do it!
あー、じゃあ、じゃあ、あの、キュー振りしてもらってもいいですか？
Ah, well, then, could you give the cue for the VTR?
あ、キュー振り？ いいよ！
Ah, the cue? Sure!
じゃあ、VTRのキュー振りをよろしくお願いします。
Then, please give the cue for the VTR.
はい！ では、鷹嶺ルイのグッズ発表から重大な告知まで…
Okay! Now, from Takane Lui's goods announcement to a major announcement...
3、2、1…
3, 2, 1...
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
ということで、まずは私、鷹嶺ルイからのお知らせです。
To start things off, here is an announcement from me, Takane Lui.
私が大好きなアニメ『陰の実力者になりたくて！』第1期のオープニングテーマ、
From my favorite anime, 'The Eminence in Shadow' season 1 opening theme,
OxTさんの『HIGHEST』の歌ってみたが近日公開されます！
my cover of 'HIGHEST' by OxT will be released soon!
シャドウ様の格好をした鷹嶺ルイにも注目！
Keep an eye out for Takane Lui dressed as Shadow-sama too!
そして、そして、なんと！
And, and, believe it or not!
同じくアニメ『カゲジツ』第1期エンディングテーマ、
The ending theme from season 1 of the same anime,
『Darling in the Night』の歌ってみたも近日公開予定です！
'Darling in the Night' cover will also be released soon!
こちらは同じく『カゲジツ』が大好きな、ねね先輩とのコラボになっております。
This one is a collaboration with Nene-senpai, who also loves the series.
ソロもコラボもお楽しみに待ってて下さいね！
Please look forward to both the solo and collab covers!
さあ、ここからはグッズ紹介の前に、
Now, before we move on to the goods introduction,
なにやらある方から発表があるらしいですよ。
it seems someone has an announcement to make.
一体、誰からの発表なんでしょうか？
I wonder who it could be?
それでは、どうぞ！
Here they are!
こんるいるい。我、名はシャドウ。
Kon-Lui-Lui. My name is Shadow.
陰に潜み、陰を狩る者。
I lurk in the shadows to hunt the shadows.
ということで、ルイさんからバトンタッチされたのでお知らせです。
Since Lui-san passed the baton to me, here is the announcement.
YouTubeのチームキャラバンチャンネルで実施の、
On the Team Caravan YouTube channel,
『陰の実力者になりたくて！マスターオブガーデン』周年当日生放送に、
during the 'Master of Garden' anniversary live broadcast,
鷹嶺ルイさんの出演が決定しました！
it's been decided that Takane Lui-san will be appearing!
なにやらそこで重大発表もあるみたいなので要チェックです。
There will be a major announcement there too, so check it out.
いつもカゲジツ、そしてカゲマスを応援してくれているルイさんの出演、楽しみにしています。
I'm looking forward to the appearance of Lui-san, who always supports the series and the game.
さて、ここからは、鷹嶺ルイ活動2周年記念グッズの紹介をさせていただきます。
Now, allow me to introduce the Takane Lui 2nd Anniversary Goods.
まずは、複製サイン入りアクリルスタンド。
First, the Reproduce Signed Acrylic Stand.
今回はMyungYi先生にイラストを書き下ろしていただきました。
This time, MyungYi-sensei provided the newly drawn illustration.
つくねモチーフのオリジナル部屋着がキュートでオシャレ。
The original Tsukune-motif room-wear is both cute and stylish.
複製サイン入りなので絶対欲しい。
It comes with a reproduced signature, so it's a must-have.
続いては、ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。
Next is the Random Acrylic Keyholder.
今回のライブテーマ『ANIMAL』にちなんで、
Based on the live show theme, 'ANIMAL',
動物と一緒のルイさんが4種類。
there are four types featuring Lui-san with animals.
イラストはYM先生の書き下ろし。
The illustrations are newly drawn by YM-sensei.
お次はこちら。ルイのチョーカー風ブレスレット。
Next is this one: Lui's Choker-style Bracelet.
ルイさんの特徴的なチョーカーがブレスレットに。
Lui-san's iconic choker has been turned into a bracelet.
腕につけてもよし、バッグにつけてもよし。
You can wear it on your wrist or attach it to your bag.
使い方はあなた次第。推しと同じアイテムを身につけられるチャンス！
It's up to you how to use it. A chance to wear the same item as your oshi!
続いて、つくね＆つみれヘアバンド。
Next, the Tsukune & Sumire Hairband.
つくねとつみれをモチーフにしたデザインが可愛い。
The design based on Tsukune and Sumire is adorable.
もこもこふわふわな素材にこだわったとのことで、2個3個と買うのもあり。
Made with extra fluffy material, you might want to buy two or three.
最後に、記念ボイス。
Lastly, the Commemorative Voice pack.
今回は『はじめての動物園デート』をテーマに、
The theme this time is 'First Date at the Zoo',
ルイさんが書き下ろしたシナリオに注目。
with a script written by Lui-san herself.
もちろん、フルセットもあります。
Of course, a full set is also available.
フルセットの購入特典は、直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと特典ボイス。
Bonuses for the full set include a hand-signed cheki-style card and bonus voice.
そして、直筆サイン入りフルセット、今回なんと、無制限！
And the hand-signed full set is, surprisingly, unlimited this time!
サイン入りのチェキは初のグッズかなので、お買い忘れのないように。
Since this is the first signed cheki merch, make sure you don't miss out.
以上、鷹嶺ルイ2周年記念グッズの紹介でした。
That concludes the introduction of Takane Lui's 2nd Anniversary Goods.
ということでナレーションを担当したのは、
The narration was provided by
『陰の実力者になりたくて！』シド、そしてシャドウ役の声優、山下誠一郎でした。
Seiichiro Yamashita, the voice actor for Cid and Shadow from 'The Eminence in Shadow'.
改めてルイさん、活動2周年おめでとうございます。
Lui-san, congratulations once again on your 2nd anniversary.
ええ、本当にholoXさんはですね、
Well, truthfully, regarding holoX,
私がホロライブさんを推させていただいてから、
ever since I started supporting Hololive,
デビュー配信を初めてリアタイできたユニット、グループということで、
they were the first unit whose debut streams I could watch in real-time,
本当にこと特別な、あの、思い入れというか、があるんですけれども。
so I really have a very special attachment to them.
そんな中でもルイさんはデビュー当初からいろいろな企画だったり、
And among them, Lui-san, from the very beginning, with various projects,
様々なチャレンジをして、それを成功させていく、
taking on various challenges and making them successful...
その成長している姿をファンのみなさまに見せているっていうところで、
Showing that growth to all of your fans,
本当に尊敬しております、日々。はい。
I truly respect you every day for that. Yes.
ライブだったらこう『Gloss』とか『MGD』とか、
Whether it's live shows like 'Gloss' or 'MGD',
あと企画とかでも『手作りdeショー』とか、『ホストクラブ ルイズ』…
or projects like 'Tezukuri de Show' and 'Host Club Lui's'...
山下誠一郎
Seiichiro Yamashita
ゲヴィーク...など、色々、なんだろう、色んな事に取り組んで、挑戦して、
Gevic... etc. various, what should I call it, tackling various things, challenging herself,
ちょっとポンも...うっ、あったりとか無かったりとかしつつ、
and with a bit of 'pon' (clumsiness)... *ahem* happening now and then,
日々頑張っている姿にこちらも、なんか背筋が伸びるというか、
seeing her work hard every day makes me straighten my posture too, or rather,
あ、俺も自分の仕事頑張ろうって思わせて頂いております。
it makes me think, "Ah, I should work hard at my job too."
最近だと、えっと、あれ何だっけ？
Recently, um, what was that?
リファインドセルフ？あの賢者すごく、もう本当に...
Refind Self? That sage was really, just truly...
撮れ高に愛された女幹部って感じで最高でした。はい。
like a female executive loved by the camera, it was great. Yes.
ということで、本当にいつも尊敬そして、応援させて頂いております。
And so, I truly always respect and support you.
これからの活動がどうか素晴らしいものになりますよう応援しております。
I'm rooting for your future activities to be wonderful.
そして、ルイ友さん、ホロリスの皆様も聞いて頂いてありがとうございました。
And, to the Lui-tomo and Holoris out there, thank you for listening.
それでは、ここからはルイさんにお返しします。
Well then, I'll hand it back to Lui-san from here.
I...
AM...
ATOMIC.
はい、ということで、重大発表もありの、ちょっと告知Vを見て頂きましたが、
Right, so, along with the major announcement, you just saw the notification video,
皆さんいかがだったでしょうかー！
How was it, everyone?!
いや、ちょっと本当にびっくりすることばかりで、えー、ちょっと私もドキドキしてるんですけど、
Wow, there were just so many surprising things, um, I'm feeling a bit nervous too,
やっぱりね、好きを伝えるっていうことは大事だなと、このね、2年間で、えー、思いました。
but I've felt over these past two years that, yeah, it's important to convey what you love.
好きを伝えれば叶うことだったりね、えー、好きにこう、携わらせて頂くことが多いなと。
If you share your passions, things can come true, and I feel I've had many opportunities to be involved with things I like.
本当に、えー、ありがとうございます、皆さん。応援ありがとうございます。
Truly, um, thank you, everyone. Thank you for your support.
そして、えー、グッズ紹介はですね、えー、私の大好きな、そのカゲジツのシャドウ様役をやっている山下さんに
And, um, for the goods introduction, I had Mr. Yamashita, who plays Lord Shadow in 'Kagejitsu' (The Eminence in Shadow), which I love,
今回紹介して頂きましたー！どう、びっくりしたでしょう？
introduce them this time! So, were you surprised?
はい、グッズに関してはですね、今回1万円以下で買えるフルセットが買えるようになっておりまして、
Yes, regarding the goods, this time we have a full set available for under 10,000 yen,
えー、直筆サインが無制限になっておりますので、
and, um, the handwritten autographs are unlimited,
1枚1枚ね、気持ちを込めて書かせて頂きますので、
so I'll be writing each and every one with all my heart,
ぜひぜひ、みんな、あの、お手元に迎え入れてくれたら嬉しいなって思います。2周年の記念に。
so I'd be really happy if everyone could get their hands on one. As a 2nd anniversary memento.
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please look forward to it!
そして、えー、ここまでやってきた2周年ライブ、『ANIMAL』なんですけど、
And, um, for this 2nd anniversary live, 'ANIMAL', that we've done so far,
残り3曲になっておりまーす！
there are only 3 songs left!
3曲ね、ちょっと続けて歌わせて頂くんですけど、
I'll be singing these 3 songs in a row,
この3曲は、とある、えー、クリエイターさんの曲を、ま、連続して歌わせて頂くんですけど、
and these 3 songs are all by a certain creator, and I'll be singing them consecutively,
最後の曲がオリジナル曲になっておりまーす！
and the very last one is an original song!
オリジナル曲ね、もう2周年までやってこれたのはみんなのおかげなので、
For the original song, since I've made it to my 2nd anniversary thanks to everyone,
ちょっと私をテーマに作った曲でございます。
it's a song created with me as the theme.
女幹部という肩書きで、ちょっと強気な感じに見えますが、
With the title of 'Female Executive', I might seem a bit aggressive,
えー、2周年やってみて、ま、ポンコツだったり、
but over these two years, well, I've been clumsy (ponkotsu),
高嶺って苗字がついてるのに、ま、高嶺の花っぽくなかったりとか、
and despite having the surname 'Takane', I haven't exactly been a 'Takane no hana' (unreachable flower),
すると、みんなもうっすらというか、もう気づいてると思いますが、
as I'm sure you've all vaguely... or rather, fully noticed by now,
そういった、えー、私をテーマにした楽曲になってますので、楽しみに、して、いて、ください！
it's a song themed around that side of me, so please look forward to it!
はい、で、続いての曲は、
Right, so the next song is...
えー、ダンサーさんとちょっと踊らせて歌わせて頂ければなと思いますので、ちょっと呼び込みたいと思います。
Um, I'd like to sing and dance a bit with some dancers, so I'll call them out.
マタさん、ヤッコさーん！
Mata-san, Yakko-san!
はーい、今日は来てくださってありがとうございます。はい。
Hi! Thank you for coming today. Yes.
えー、続いての曲はね、『バニー』という曲なんですけれど、
Um, the next song is called 'Bunny',
『バニー』という曲が、マタさんとヤッコさんが、えー、オリジナルで踊っている、
'Bunny' is a song that Mata-san and Yakko-san have an original dance for,
ちょっと動画を拝見させて頂きまして、ぜひ一緒にパフォーマンスしたいなということで今回お呼びさせて頂きましたー！
I saw their video and really wanted to perform it together, so I invited them here this time!
ちょっと緊張するんですけど、
I'm a little nervous,
ちょっと近くでパフォーマンス見れるのもめちゃくちゃ嬉しい！ははっ！
but I'm also so happy to see their performance up close! Haha!
ということで、3曲連続で聞いてください！『バニー』！
So, please listen to these 3 songs in a row! 'Bunny'!
バニーバニーガール　今夜はもっと　期待して恋して　マドモアゼル
Bunny, bunny girl, tonight, expect more and fall in love, Mademoiselle
バニー
Bunny
どうにもこうにもならない分かってるけど　あなたと全私だけ
I know it's no use, but it's just you and all of me
にっちもさっちもどうにも詰まるけど　二兎追うもん何せ間抜け時
Caught in a bind, but chasing two hares is just foolishness
くねるくねるばかりの私生活です　ビジネス人参朝と昼晩
A private life that's just full of twists and turns, business carrots morning, noon, and night
きっちりばっちりあなたの前だけは　つけまにハイヒールリップサービス
Perfectly, at least in front of you, false eyelashes, high heels, and lip service
バニーバニーバニー　つけた耳　垂れているバニー
Bunny, bunny, bunny, ears on, drooping bunny
塞いじゃえ　とん、とん　バニー
Close them up, tap, tap, bunny
うさっちゃえ 分じゃえ 待ったわに
Let's bunny up, share it, wait a while
ワーチュウガオソバに
I'll be right by your side
転んだり噛んだり可愛いじゃん
Falling and biting, isn't it cute?
あざとさに長けてる
Expert in being calculatingly cute
バニバニガー アー ヤバい度
Bunny-bunny girl, ah, the danger level
ハマっちゃいなよ ね？
You'll get hooked, right?
バニバニガー アー
Bunny-bunny girl, ah
求愛モード
In courtship mode
期待して恋して
Expect more, fall in love
メロメロ ヘイ！
Head over heels, hey!
うっかりぽっちゃりなれないの ウェイトは機密
I can't accidentally get chubby, my weight is a secret
やっぱり当然乙女だもん
After all, of course, I'm a maiden
きっちりバッチリ咲かせるルージュの花を
Making rouge flowers bloom perfectly
お口に塗って軽めのウィンク
Paint them on my lips and give a light wink
バニ バニバニ
Bunny, bunny-bunny
背のファスナー
The zipper on the back
下ろせない バニー
I can't pull it down, Bunny
うさっちゃえ 分じゃえ 待ったわに
Let's bunny up, share it, wait a while
ワーチュウガオソバに
I'll be right by your side
怒ったり泣いたり可愛いじゃん
Getting angry or crying, isn't it cute?
リテラシー欠けてる
Lacking in literacy
バニバニガー アー 若い度
Bunny-bunny girl, ah, youth level
踊っちゃいなよ ね？
Why don't you dance? Right?
バニバニガー アー
Bunny-bunny girl, ah
酒耐モード
In alcohol tolerance mode
期待してそして
Expect more, and then
ボロボロ ヘイ！
Worn out, hey!
くだんない範疇で
Within a trivial range
たぶっちゃえ もっちゃえ ニキショウバイ
Deceive them, take them, business is good
うさっちゃえ 飛んじゃえ だったチャーミング
Bunny up, fly high, was so charming
愛取るだのバニー
Like an idol, Bunny
転んだり噛んだり可愛いじゃん
Falling and biting, isn't it cute?
あざとさに長けてる
Expert in being calculatingly cute
バニバニガー アー ヤバい度
Bunny-bunny girl, ah, the danger level
ハマっちゃいなよ ね？
You'll get hooked, right?
バニバニガー アー
Bunny-bunny girl, ah
求愛モード
In courtship mode
期待して恋してメロメロ
Expect more, fall in love, head over heels
痒いけど愛して バニバニ ヘイ！
It's irritating, but love me, Bunny-bunny, hey!
あーあ 人生ゲームね フクロウさん
Ah, it's the game of life, isn't it, Mr. Owl?
まだ面倒なんてやだったった
I still hated dealing with trouble
ラスト2曲！盛り上がっていきましょう！
Last two songs! Let's get excited!
全然足りないテスト赤点
Failing grades on tests, nowhere near enough
仕方がないから石を投げ
Nothing I can do but throw stones
万年冴えない私に万歳
Cheers to the forever dull me
努力がないから恨まれる
Resented because I don't put in the effort
ホロリホロリと泣き声が
Tearfully, tearfully, the sound of crying
ポロリポロリ溢れだした
Trickle, trickle, it started to overflow
のらりくらりと生きたいな
I want to live aimlessly, idly
そろりそろりじゃいけないの
Tiptoeing along just won't do
やりがいなんてない 怠けていたい
There's no fulfillment, I just want to be lazy
決めものになれない
I can't become a deciding factor
あーあ 人生ゲームね フクロウさん
Ah, it's the game of life, isn't it, Mr. Owl?
もう関係ない ほら関係ない
It doesn't matter anymore, see, it doesn't matter
何年たってもフクロウさん まだ面倒なんてやー！
No matter how many years pass, Mr. Owl, trouble is still a no!
オーマイガー社会では
Oh my god, in society
ヤンキーなんかじゃいけないよ
You can't just be a delinquent
オーマイガー世間では
Oh my god, in the world
苦労が美徳になるからだったった ヘイ！
Suffering becomes a virtue, and that was that, hey!
天才少年は孤独を抱いて
The boy genius embraces his loneliness
愛なんてないから眠れない
He can't sleep because there's no love
天然少女は容姿も照れ
The airheaded girl is shy about her looks
わざとじゃないから睨まれる
She gets glared at, though it's not on purpose
ホロリホロリと泣き声が
Tearfully, tearfully, the sound of crying
ポロリポロリ明日濡らした
Trickle, trickle, it soaked tomorrow
のらりくらりと生きたいな
I want to live aimlessly, idly
そろりそろりじゃうるさいの
Just tiptoeing is annoying
あー問題だらけのフクロウさん
Ah, Mr. Owl is full of problems
でも最強じゃん ほら最強じゃん
But he's the strongest, see, he's the strongest
将来なるならフクロウさん ただ根性なんてねー
If I become anything, let it be Mr. Owl, just no willpower...
オーマイガー奴らには
Oh my god, for them
見えないものが多すぎて
There are too many things they can't see
オーマイガー世間では
Oh my god, in the world
真面目が美学になるからだったった ヘイ！
Seriousness becomes an aesthetic, and that was that, hey!
何も背負わないで 無責任と流さないで
Don't carry anything, don't brush it off as irresponsibility
あなたが今飛べるなら フクロウでもいいんじゃないの
If you can fly now, isn't being an owl just fine?
あーあ 人生ゲームね フクロウさん
Ah, it's the game of life, isn't it, Mr. Owl?
もう関係ない ほら関係ない
It doesn't matter anymore, see, it doesn't matter
何年たってもフクロウさん まだ面倒...
No matter how many years pass, Mr. Owl, trouble is still...
反動だなんて嫌
I don't want any backlash
オーマイガ
Oh my God
社会ではヤンキーな格好じゃいけないの
In society, you shouldn't dress like a delinquent
オーマイガ
Oh my God
世間では苦悩が美徳になるからさ
Because in the world, suffering becomes a virtue
少しは中指立てちゃえば パパッヘイ
If you just flip the bird a little, pa-pa-hey!
ホロホーク
作詞・作曲:すりぃ
Holohawk
Lyrics & Composition: Surii
単純で明快で混沌じゃない
It's simple and clear, not chaotic
まだ想像と空想と偏見でファイ
Still fighting with imagination, fantasy, and prejudice
そりゃ完全な万全な設定じゃない
Well, that's not a perfect, foolproof setting
からかってくれないか
Won't you tease me?
外見と内面と偶像の不一致
Discrepancy between appearance, inner self, and idol
この繊細さ敏感さ共有しよう
Let's share this delicacy and sensitivity
ほら冷徹な表情は笑顔っちょハイ
Look, those cool expressions are smiling faces, high!
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's put it away and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, let's carry those expectations and go
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's put it away and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, let's carry those expectations and go
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
I don't want to be treated like an unattainable flower
あのね誰も彼も私と勘違い
You know, everyone is misunderstanding me
驚きの愛
A surprising love
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
ポンコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just having a bit of a klutzy side makes me feel familiar
その才その際その体受け止めてよね
Please accept that talent, that occasion, that body
高嶺の未来 乾杯
Cheers to the future of Takane
ノーイグしっかりウォッチ
No-ignore, watch closely
アイアイユーノー 煽りとか苦手
Aye aye, you know? I'm not good at provocations
モーキンルイね 一見クールげ
Bird of prey Lui, right? Looks cool at first
意外とギャップ系 イメージ大変身
Surprisingly a gap-moe type, image transformation
大衆の感性で内緒じゃない
It's not a secret with the public's sensibility
ありゃ心配ね相談ね散々ねもう
Oh, that's worrying, a consultation, it's terrible already
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない
It's not just a stream of sound arguments or irrationality
個人的見解 対正解
Personal opinion vs. the correct answer
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
捕食しないさ だから怖がっちゃ嫌
I won't prey on you, so don't be afraid
ほらね爪も羽もお洒落に研いで
See, I've sharpened my claws and feathers stylishly
隠しちゃいない
I'm not hiding them
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
観察眼がちょいあるだけで緊張感
Just having a bit of an observant eye brings tension
その才その際その体受け止めてよね
Please accept that talent, that occasion, that body
高まる時代 乾杯
Cheers to the rising era
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's put it away and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, let's carry those expectations and go
はいはいお姉さんしまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's put it away and go
はいはい期待感背負っちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, let's carry those expectations and go
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
I don't want to be treated like an unattainable flower
あのね誰も彼も私と勘違い
You know, everyone is misunderstanding me
驚きの愛
A surprising love
ホロホロホーク ホロホークだけど
Holo-holo-hawk, Holohawk, but
ポンコツみがちょいあるだけで親近感
Just having a bit of a klutzy side makes me feel familiar
その才その際その体受け止めてよね
Please accept that talent, that occasion, that body
高まる時代 乾杯
Cheers to the rising era
おいちょ
Oicho!
高まる時代 乾杯
Cheers to the rising era
このあと24時から先ほど披露した
Starting from 24:00 today, the 5th original song
鷹嶺ルイ5曲目のオリジナル曲「ホロホーク」が
各種音楽サイトで配信開始されます！
by Takane Lui, "Holohawk," which I just performed,
will be available on various music streaming sites!
私のカバー曲でも人気の高いフクロウさんと、
It's a completely original song created by Fukurou-san,
「エゴロック」を制作したすりぃさんによる
完全書き下ろし楽曲になっております。
who is also popular in my cover songs, and Surii-san,
who produced "Ego Rock."
ちょっと真面目でお堅そうに見えるけど、
It expresses a side of Takane Lui who
実はポンコツだし親しみやすいんだよ、という
鷹嶺ルイを表現した一曲になっております。
looks serious but is actually a klutz and easy to get along with.
すりぃさんのアニマルシリーズらしさも出ていて、
It has the characteristic style of Surii-san's
一度聴いたら忘れられないキャッチーな曲に
なっているので、たくさん聴いてほしいです。
"Animal series," making it a catchy song you won't forget,
so I hope you'll listen to it a lot.
そして24時からの配信に先駆けまして、
And ahead of the release at midnight,
このあと22時5分から「ホロホーク」のMVを
プレミア公開いたします！
the music video for "Holohawk" will have its premiere
at 22:05 today!
こだわって作りましたので、絶対見てくださいね！
I put a lot of care into making it, so please be sure to watch it!
メンバーシップ限定ライブもあります。
There is also a membership-exclusive live.
まだまだアニマルは終わらない！
ANIMAL isn't over yet!
メンバーシップライブも盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped for the membership live as well!
2周年アコースティックライブ
メンバーシップ限定
2nd Anniversary Acoustic Live
Membership Exclusive
2周年LIVE見てくれて本当にありがとう！
この2年間楽しかったけど、
Thank you so much for watching the 2nd Anniversary LIVE!
The past two years have been fun, but...
つらくてくじけそうだった日もありました。
でもこうやって無事に2周年をむかえられたのは、
...there were also days when it was painful
and I felt like giving up.
But the reason I was able to reach this
2nd anniversary safely like this...
みんなの支えがあったからこそです！
本当に感謝してもしきれない...
...is precisely because of everyone's support!
I really can't thank you enough...
これからも一緒に色々な夢を叶えていこうね！！
みんながいればどんな困難も
Let's keep making various dreams come true together!!
I feel like I can overcome any difficulty...
乗りこえられる気がするよ！！よろしくね！！
2023.11.27 Lui Love you だーいすき！！
...if I have everyone with me!! Looking forward to it!!
2023.11.27 Lui Love you, Love ya!!